{"qu1":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 1 and 2:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Zap, Wow and Whoosh are three models of small cars of three different manufacturers. The mileage (in km\/litre) of Wow is 15% more than that of Zap. The fuel consumption (in litres\/km) of Whoosh is 10% more than that of Zap. By what percent is the mileage of Wow higher than that of Whoosh? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>26%\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>26.5%\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>24.5%\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>25%\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu2":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 1 and 2:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Find the HCF of <img height=\"34\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAIoAAAAiCAYAAACAyEHnAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAABCwSURBVHhe7VwJWI7LF69sleIW13JLqKzd7PtSuKSEZAvpZq3sKmS79uVSSVlakETJmn1L2aLs6yXr\/SNkF1minP+c8877fe+3ZAlXefyeZ57eOWfe+d6ZOTNzzpkzaYAEb99mQnBwMLi7u1Nav34D56ji+fPnVCYx8TCnyBEXFwceHkIdM2bMgH\/\/9z\/OyT1u374N06ZOpTqHDx8OR44kcY4ce3bvlv2un58\/pKenc44c+xISiI9pXkAAteNHQHZ2NoSFhkI8a58ytm3bKmvz4sXB8ObNG84RcPHiPzB2rA\/xfXx84Pz5C5wjh4Kg9OjhBBoaGlC9enUwNTWl5+kzZnKuIkaOGE789Rs2coqAGdOngaamJpiYlIfatWtTmSpVqrKBTuUlPh+PHz2CmjVrUF1Yp6GBARQrXhz27o3nJQDCw5dBoUKFoFSpUlCzhlD2j9ZtICsrm5cAWLokDAoXLgRGRsZQg5exsWnLufkb\/n6+oMna4zFoMKcImPP336DFxqNixYpgYWFBbXZy6sG5ACmXLkH58iZQoEABqFOnDhQqWBCMjcvB+QuKwiITlKDAQKpk7Nhx8P79e8hkUtfF0ZFoZ8+e46UALl9OgUYNGxAdU8SKSM4BOHo0mWhW1i1kszl24waiWbdoSfXmBu1sbamOTZs3U\/7OnVQoZ2wMBoYlqM5bN28S3+J3S3jw4AGVCV+2jGiTJk+hPHYI5lu1+kO2inh7exEtIGA+5fMrEuLjqR2Y+vbrz6kAhxMTidatuxO8plXkPfzp4kK0mJg1VAbHslChwmzsjlL+5IkToKOjDbVq16G8CJmgXLl8GSJXrGCd+IJTAFZELKdKE\/btp\/zjx49JOk1NzaBvnz7Ei4iQC8qePXugYcOGkJSUzCkCqlWtAvr6xeH1a8Ul71OBDV65ahXPCejs2Il+\/8WLDHj69AmsW7cOTrBGish48YL4Awa4Ud5z5AjKX7lylfIioqOj4Pr16zyX\/\/Ds2TNaYS0sfqf2ufbpxzlsh3DqTrTHT55wCrAV9h21OTVVWOHNzUyhHFv9pahcyRyM2KoihcLWIyIjIwMOHjgAlczNoVat2uxjhNXh0cOHsCBoAdvjMiE6ahV9hFRQ1OHVy5egp1cU7NrZc8qX4eHDB7CCCbSenh706z9AZZV69+4dXL16FXo7O0Nxtj3t33+A6M2aNIHSZcqSUIwbNxZ69eoFCxYsJF5+hr2dHZQrZwLHjx2j8fjTtS\/Rs7OyaPwsLCzZ5LgCnp6e4Mz6ZClbaaWYNXMmbdkjRoxkfbUfRnl7s+25MEyeMpWXEKAiKC\/YTKzA9iz8UUzrclBoFy9a+EmC4tyrJ5U7dfo0p+QeyUlJoKWlRfWVKFESbvz7L+fI4TZwoOzbpcuwuZkZFC1alHQUFCAjIyMqU6duvXyr0M4PmEdtOHnyFKQyZR+fRUHBcSxZogS1tQDrs5IlS0Lp0qWpDOpuokL7ninBLaytiS6mpk2bsZUni\/giVAQFV5PV0dFseYpm20gDtl\/pwKZNgm4gRfDiRVTphwTF9U9hP1y2LJxTvgy4GkSvXs0098VQtmwZUkpv3FAUll07dzJrbT0M5AIziCl3uOpUrlRJyA8ewrbA11R28qRJRJs8RdBj8hPOnDlNCqif\/zzK32SWJbZloNsgyqOg\/MqEA2kT\/5okG\/ihQwYTLTRsCfVLe3t7yk+dNh0OHz4Mk\/76i\/Jt29oqWEdqtx4Rd9g+hi81btKUU+T4kKCgsLVq2YL4q1ZFcerXxZqY1VS\/qKyqQ7NmTakMWlz169Wl5zt37nKuAH19PVK08xNwe61Zw5Lag4p4UFAQmbWYb9CgIYQyM\/np06dgbPQbFGSK6stXr\/ibAOlMp9HU1AA3dw+4xrZofGfI0GGcK8DLcyTR4xP2cYpEUHZs307+iVevhNmGyHqXBQULaEF1pigpIydBucFmPZqyxYoVh8TDRzj1yzA\/IIAkXopj3MIa4zMW7qelMQvGW0WJdmF7Mpa5l3YfBvTrS8+pqXc4V4CBwS9kpeUnoN5nZmrKvt2A2qSc9PT0aRxtbdpQPiPjJX8TyJpFgwRX1sOJh4gfGbmScwXErI4menBwKKdIBGX40KHEDAqSK3gb2BKONGfn3pwihzpBQUvD8ncLKPlrKUi7f59TvxyVzM3ot3AvFuHtJZi2GzbGMosthZ6lA37v7l02o4zYHv0LZGZmwqqVkVRm9OgxvARAFLOkkDZ+wkROyR\/ALQOtnSfMmhHToYMHqS09ejrTaoJARRVpc+b6Uh6Bkw5pS5Yug2esHD7Xr99ApqdlZr5hu0FLol\/45yLREDJBuXf3Hil8WMDW1g5s27alZzOmOatzlgXM8yd+SMgSTgGYMH480VCLRueOGatPTI0aNYaXbCbkBvv374OCBQtS3d26dWOWWC167tTJkVY9RH++YlSrXh26d+\/OvkEoLyrjKCxWzZsRrbmVFTg4ONBzhYqmzJJ6SGXyAtBiCwkJkZmvn4rz585Re7p2c+IUgOfp6WziCmZzGxsbaNfOjp7RkkX1AIEeWaShsuvk5ETON8x7enkTX4SCjoJL+Ai2\/VSpUpm8qUPZKoOuc3U4wEwpdPlKXenoQkZav379oGfPngoJlUpl1\/Hn4GhyMhOAbiR0OAOmTZ8OWUxjlyIoKBAaN25MZTp16gQ7mGIrBa54s2fNAktLSzBnE2Ao25uVdZbvjYjl4TRQO3fu4pRPA44T9v3y5Ss4RQBOgokTJ0C1qlWhcuXKMGaMj4JfBREdFQUtmU6J\/WZlZQ2RKxW3IsQHldmf+O+xft1aEhTp8URewE9B+QLgscB0trLhiuni4gKBzPpATzEC9QTcQo6fOMGUw9Xk4Bs0eDB5r6VAr7Kvry\/xfX396Dzqp6D8QFi7dg0NKCZcstFTjM+oUKP5ejlFULALFBB0JRMTuRMzNnYT1XGfKfyiDoEOQPSLoH6H+b3xqqfA3xM\/BSUXQKsDPc5lypSB69dvcCpAl87CIeqjR4\/poBJPc3V1i8LBg4eILx7eOTAlHDF8mGBphjDdDoFOM3S7\/xSUHxRoqqakXILezr0oxEIUFBxw+\/YdeCkB+npFoaNDJ3o2KWcMxuVM6FnE6ugoei8ur209CQkJZE526dLlP0sYzISBNh8CLt+jR49W+\/63TP7+\/ioHjeqAMTJeXl5QoUJ5GlgxFS6irSAoXbt2528Izi4UFMfOXShfpHBh2bMIMRxi9544TpED+wz7Tt13f8vk6uoKGueY\/T2LmYz4Af9ViomJ+ehg4NlEeHi42ve\/ZYqNjeVfkDNQiJs0bkQD2rFjR\/Dz84MdO3bAIA930NTSgidPnsoEpXPnrvwtVUEpXkwf6jdoSM8i0O2A7+2J28spcmCfYd+p++5vmXDy\/Nx6coGrV67QYNrbK24r1lbNiX479Q7cvnUrR0Hp0NGB8g4dOlAZaWCY28ABRPupo0iAe3sftqx5jxoNb9++5dS8gVMnT0Lfvn0hODiEU+R4+uQJBQtpaGhSRODMmTPJgYcDjAkP09Lu3aNnOzt5HE7m69dEa\/VHa8pj2ATmizKLafbs2RRDI9axa7eiGf298V0FBb2GRr+VpY6RHlzlBaCFUqRIEWjUqAmnKCI+fq8sjleLmbWOjp0hIiKCIvy2bNlKp7T47OMzjr8B8DYzE1q2sAYv71GcArB92zaoVasm1VOaWVH+fv7kXU4+eoyXyBvIUVCSk5MhLS3ngz08iMIy0gAXPFiSHlRJU07nPJuYToDBvLjvfwpQuDC+MztbUcfBGBN1v6scgHP92jU4cuSI2khzZQzo319F2VQG\/sbXCHzCej6m4OcE1F1wLNLTVb8Dj02OHTtK\/FeScAMROC7S\/sKEzkJlHVKtoIjHzKGh8gM\/ZbSwtgINTS2FKxG1+WGdNOnr61OUFW4vysAZ1ojNujlz5nLKx4FxJTq6ReENe1cK9GHo6uqq\/H5KymXiZ2dnwTB+Qi6mFi1awoMH6g8ErzGBMjY2VnstJK9hymQhAGv\/gYOcIgBjYzEIXWwvrlhSzzBOoqZNmoC2dhFZGUzFiv9CAiOFiqAsCQsDLS1NeiF8eQSnyoEVODBNH\/m\/liqtMJvQVY1BNGLCABpLS8HzGKsmSg4\/9MKFf3juw8DoelsbG6qrnEkFBUF59eolsyCKgZmZucLvBwUtkB25\/zVxAr3r5u4O+\/bto9hQzNu0tVVrgaEegsKS1yFG6WE6dCiRUwFOnzpFNANDQ4o32bVrFwlNEWa+i32O4ZPoFKzfoIFCv4WGhqkc4MoE5U3mG5kAVKhQgf4qC0oSW7JLsB\/GvRvjMQ1LlPzgsovl0QE1ShIDkhtgmEExtjLp6OhSsM5vRsYKgnLlymX6XuXgJhEPmZDhNzdurKhvdOvaFXr3dlE5hc4PwIlTv149and5fjwgFRRvL0+i7YmT+2PwohfSBg8ZSnkxhmVVVDTlPwSZoKSl3aNLUXh3ZmWkEOQTHq4oKIHz54N9+\/Zw8+ZN2jK0tXVyFJT09GcUs1mxoinTPxT1hM\/F38wicHR0pKN0SwsLus8jFZTY2I30vcEhIXSfZ9GiRXDixEnOFeJokY9nLDhTUEe5oHTBKb8Bo+7r1KnL9LVjMHGCEAckFZQu\/DqLdGXAlVNXR5uudiAWLghiZTTpjg\/eEEUL7+JFebCSFDJBkSqTYaEh9CPKgoLBPyJqsC0FZ3hOgjJzxgyqY\/PmLZySe2Rmyk1ns4oVaSWTCorYUcoJg4oRgfOFqC7nXs5gyFZEkd+yVSt49PgxlclvkLoTxFubUkHxcHMj2vHj8rtOqMgXZBZazZq1Kd+3j6usL6Rp0aLFxJdCrTIbGhJMLygLihQY3JuToGCIHW4VouR+TZibmqoIylgfH7pKijoJKqdnz56FunXrUBtOnz7DZs4CWSdgKCRGm4uhlHju8nGHfd6GOkFJPCTEw5YpUxa2bN0K27dvp+AlpGEANgJ9WMiPioqiy31HWL+YsomIZc6dO09lRHwTQRHjU8PCcraacgt1goJQNi3RYYbfgNaW2B4PD8V7uR3YNor0WzlE8eUXqBMUBG7DaHUiDxNeLa1apQpUrlKVl0CDQrHftm7ZTGXF1VjENxGUdna2FFfx8NEjTvl6UBYUtJxQZ7p+Q37cj8BDO2xDL2cXiNuzm57n+vpxrgDfuXOILprQ+RU5CQriZUYGJCUlyXQPfT098gxjv924fkMlNjfl0kWqy91duB8k4qsLCpqqujo60NzKmlO+LpQFBXUr1PoNDUtS40WIl+MXMwUNo8jwGb2nUrS3b8fomhRAlJ+hTlDQyYaX4G7evMUpGMIg+McC5geSjqOjXQSqVbfgXAFBgfOpzNp16zhFgFpBEa+LLl2a8w2\/6tWqUvSWsqCcOX2a3h3p6cUpXxcmxsagp19MYeuZwJVZvD1wkJl8kZEr6PANfQipd4R7PGJQ0bBhw0lH8fIUzEdXfgUzP0O8\/XdA4nDD\/wODNMsaNclvhP+AAK+WGhgYypyMrvw\/G\/RmfxNZnyxcKIw7+qOU\/7eMWkHZtnULVKpUCXbtyvlgyrGTA1ha1uA5OXDpwnc\/N4r8U2HTurXK0Txi\/LhxtB9jOCFe7WjYsJHKP\/DxcHcj7y3ycTXEKPwfAfi\/UbDPr15VdBCuiYmh1Rbva2O\/4L\/8UC6DfaKtrU19gupC6zZtVIQEAOD\/4uzRLLJ4QhsAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"138\" \/> . <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='28' Height= '34' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABwAAAAiCAYAAABMfblJAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAANQSURBVFhH7ZdbSFRRFIZHnYs9mM5EapmkU0lpkgp28ZKVhVqp6YxjL2KZN+pJ0CAySBFTQzAvD47dxzLI0tdG8KGLvjWgI5mak+AUBkWJhprj39nLo+PkRMcpe\/KHDWutvfb+2OfsdVhHhL9QSclV1NTc4D1hchjYUF8HsVgMTfppPiJMKwa+GxpCmloNkUgEJycnpKrU\/IwwrRh4KOYgxBIJtE1N8PbyRMLxE\/yMMK0YqNfrMTpqJlshlyM+4TjZQuXwO7TMzq4B7WoN+FsxIKvFA5FRfESYHAbOWSwoKChAbW0dHxEmh4GOag34z\/X\/gZ2dndBoNFCpVKs+MjMzIerp6UF5eTnKyspWfVRXV69dmn8vu8CRkRE0cS3EzMwPPmKVwWBAfX09tFothk0mPmrV4OAguru70dXVZTPGx8dpfhlwcmICoSF76MM8wdlLVVRYSPGlo6Kyip\/lvq9zFoSFhi7LYeP58xeUYwN829+\/uMDHZwsmJyf5GaDt6ROKBwXtxhsuzzQ8jKSkRJvN2ClcZVIcPhL75xO2t7fRYj8\/fwQHB0MuV9gAU04lw9nZGca+Pj4CfPv6FVKugzuVoiLf8Po17dF08xb59rQIvHvnNnJz8zA1NYWss2cgkUhtgAnxcVjv7sF7Vm329oav71aydffvEbC0tBT5+XnIyMhAS8sjWCxzNM9k99Jo0tSQSmU2wHRNGtf4cic0Wk\/ImmLWfSu3bSc\/+1wWAdlQKpVwc3MjOy4uHtPT05RjF8g2\/xXYwfWjbLG\/vxKPW1upPw0I2EHd985duyinouIaYmJi8PLVK\/LZ08rJyaZ1jY1aigkGMjVw5SCTyRZPkZ2Tg4gD++HlvYnPWK6PHz7AxcUZJxOTyV8RkOnL589UZ0ajkXwPD3fs3befbHZzBwYGyF7Qd24PiUSM2KPHyBcMbG7WITw8HCbTez4CPHzwgE5aWXWdfM+NG6FQbCB7QQvldOnSZfLtAlWpKVySkw1Qr39GC0NCw9DR0QFtYyPWubrC09MLY2OfKOfC+fOUk5qqotrT6XTUSsq5YTbP\/4\/YBV4sKkRgYBDvWcVKZxNXBuyisI0jIiJh5t7RUl0pLuZOqaDby+o2Kjoavb3zjx8AfgKCFOEvXpUW7AAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='30' Height= '35' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAB4AAAAiCAYAAABIiGl0AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAO1SURBVFhH7ZdbSFNxHMe3dAUbXWY667EssDSRLH0ot6wwVLrhZaTlKnqwWXSn6AIpUj1kPWUgpWkoQhniJQ0qXQrOSxfcvNR6MUzDtpXkgxry7Zzf+R91uujMwZ76wA\/O\/\/v\/HT7jnP\/57xwZvMDhsMNoNKKg4D5LpOOV+GBGOmQyGQ5kHGSJdOYtzs25TlK+kpNTWCqdeYlbmptJmJV1HH4LFmDvvv1sRjoei50OB9TLliEpaTecTif9AJ+I43fuhFodgF+jo\/j2bcg34ht5eSTq6HxLY1GcnJJKY0+QLB4eHiYJX7GxsYiOjkZERASN1Wo1jVtbzaz730gW2+12ZB46BL1ej4SEBCqdTkdiTXAwjTvZlZCCx\/d4Jg7HdxKnpulZIh2vxJ8+fSRx3PYdLJGOV+KRkRFuuyxAfX09S6Tjldgb\/ot9BonHx8d9WhMTE5BVVlYiLCwMoaGhPquYmBjI+Eeiu7sbVqvVZ9XX1\/d\/VfsOt+LR0V8oKiri\/gQcLJnmS38\/SkpKaKs0mUwsnWbk50+0t7fDbDa7lMViYR0CbsVpqSm0+b9\/\/4ElAs+4J2DRooU0J1ZiYhLt2SKPiotd5sVat2496xBwEQ8NDWFXfPxUs8ViZTPAR24l+vn5ISBgOapraujFoODePeozGI6wLuDM6VOUPXn6FG1tbVNltXazDoEpcW1tDRT+\/gjSaBAeHj5HfDc\/n7Li4kcsEdi3dw\/ldnZbtLFb6cf9iylxeXk5DhsOw\/njB06eyJ4jFt+ju2ZkPHm5uZQ3NZkwOTmJJYsXY8uWraiqqkJOTg4KCwvpSs7G7T3mX3Fmi8XLeuPmLZYIbN4URXkjJ\/46MEDHfCkUCiiVSjpeHhiIurrn7AwBt2JDZiadMFPsdDqgCQqk\/OLFS6ioqMC2bTrI5XLKmkxv0Nfbiw3cbTJmZ2NwcJD25BcNDVio8EfwipUui1CymKezowM6rZbm+IqL245zZ8\/ScXV1Deuay7GjR6mnsbGJJR6KRfq5Z3mAu6w82cbj1NvT04uxsTHYbDZM\/P5NcyJXLl+mnvqGFyzxQGzlNgCtVset\/jqWCK+8KpUSIWvW0vhO\/m0678HDIhqLJCUmUm77\/JklfxFnpAufn11d07uNuHCUShV3WavR0tKMyMhIykpLH1PPu3dvabxk6VKUlZVxz6+Z+7DLoix91qesW\/G1q1cREhJCm8RMzK2t9PUgl8nhz20mq1atnvNcv371ElFRG0nGr2yVSoXz5y+wWRHgD15hvwiCePVbAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='27' Height= '34' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABsAAAAhCAYAAAAoNdCeAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAJlSURBVEhL7ZbPa5JxHMcf1NBwp+ogbAWLaiJe1sVZswJnB93WoQKLWbEOHhpUsG4Lpl3ackF1zN1yOzSDLe0fyOxYKiikjuk6zMHSMUHxB+\/0+3yZjz022ZNPJ1\/wged5fz4Pr+c3XwYC8X1cg91ux87OL5q0R5AsHAqhr7cXMpkMe3t5mrbnULJ8Po+nMzNgGIaUXK5AKpWm3fYcSvbBu0IkLtcCRi0Wsi2aLJ1OI5lMku1r4+PiyriIfmVcujIugmUWs\/n\/ya6aTES2sZGiSXsEy2KxGILBIIrFIk3aI1gmhK6sIzC5XA6RSAThcFjUikajYLxeL7RaLdRqtail0+nY21gqlUSvcrncfRs7Q0uZbWICk5P36R6f0Pdv0Ov1+BwI0ARYXl6C1WptKpvNRlZgDoeTzPBkjtlZ8oPVDelp0kw8Hod6YIDMrK6u0RR4ueBqevs0Gg1O9\/eTuSH9BTKzL0skEhgxGklTIpHAOGKiHZZqtYpFtxtSqZTM1Mvv\/0S7rRkbtUDZ04MftROssy+7eeM6VCoVPB5PbYkmh+HSFdphWV9PEsGDqSk8mZ5uK3sxP0dm3nmWaMKRhUJhFAoFlGvfRH3oT1k2myV\/mjrzc88PlGW2tnCktoC9OGygCQvvmdUHW8m4PHM6DpQ9fvSQ9AOBLzRh4cm2M5l\/ku3u5nBUocDg4HmaNOi4zLvynvTeuhdp0qDjsnt375De5uZPmjT4q2zYcJkmfJwO9lv0+fw0YalUKjh39gz6Tp6iSTM8WbV2gFKphNkyRhM+b16\/IjPB4FeaNDhx\/Bist27TPS7Ab5oeaac29QzLAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='28' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABwAAAAgCAYAAAABtRhCAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAK8SURBVEhL7ZZJTBNRGMfbRKq2RIvFICaERcGLGovpIicF3BUBTwQTWWKboJ4xrHGpIQgUkSAxccUDphDCveCd9oJ4ootFrMGLBA5FoPh35vWzdBnIUGtP\/JIvee\/7vsyvnXlv5kkQIwsLC6irq0Nf33PKiCNmodFggEQiQWXlDcqIIyZht7mLyWQyGcrLr1NWHFsWfpqcZLKOzk4cysnGxUuXqSKOLQl9Ph8OpqcHJftTVf9XWF11EypVKpaWfrH5vhQlrlwtYWOxiBa+e\/uG3cr+\/hfwer1wOp1Q7t2D02cK4fF4sLq6Sp2bI1pYXFjIhBvFzMxX6twc0UK7zYbR0VEMDw+zsFgsSE5WQJ1\/EiMjI+z5imFLzzCS3bt24tz5CzQTR8xCv98PnU4Lg9FIGXH80z+MhW1h3Em8sKenB2q1OiGh0WggcblcsFqtCYmxsbHtRRN\/BIVPu82or79Hs2g+T02hoqICc3M\/KAO8HxhAa2trWJhMJrS1tWFiwkZdAsIPg4Psc3NCnU+ZcL7NzrKjBd\/jcDgpC5ReK4FcLg+GUqkMfrq6zN3UFSKcn\/+JxoaGYFNx8VmqBOBf1kNDFqTQhXYkJcHt\/kJVsA\/wysoKC37M\/7ADaWnQnyrA4uIidYUIO9rb2YWe9fbiSF4u9PoCqgRwc9uHr9fU1uLunduQSqVhwkjKy0q5fil3MnBRJkBQOD09zV3Azcb8LdNodGz8F\/7ga7fb2fix6RGTbyT8OD7O6vcfPKTMOoKLJic7C1qtnmbRtDQ3bSrUcm8U\/rC1vLxMmXXiLrTZJlitqbmFMuHEXWg03GI1B3eqEyKuwt9ra8jMyMDh3DzKRCMozM7KjFo0oTQ3NQoKv3PnVT5fVV1DmWgEhcePHUVRUfg+DKWr8wkUCgW3ctf3F4\/T4eA2vQIvX72mTCTAHw5xZSDzMPOrAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu3":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for question 3:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">The number 87 is divided into two parts, such that three times the first part and five times the second part are in the ratio 4 : 3. Find the lower of the two parts. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"27","CORRECT_ANSWER":"27","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu4":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 4 and 5:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Which of the following functions best describes the graph below? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhwACiAPcAAP\/\/\/\/\/\/25A6AGa2\/7ZmADqQ2\/\/bkDo6kNv\/\/9uQOv+2ZgBmtpBmADoAAAA6kP\/\/tmYAOpDb\/2YAAAAAZrb\/\/8\/Pz\/f39yAgIJeXl4eHhwAAABgYGO\/v7+fn5xAQECgoKDAwMHBwcFhYWHh4eEBAQK+vr7+\/v5+fn2BgYAgICN\/f37e3t0hISDg4OH9\/f1BQUMfHx6enpzoAZjQ0NGhoaAYGBmYAZgAAOpC2kB4eHgwMDDo6OqGhoY+Pj9uQZpBmkNfX15A6Ojo6AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAwACiAAAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypxJs6bNmzg7BhAwQCCBAjmDCmVIoKeBAwiGKl06MAHQokyjDlWw4GhSqVhvHmXQM6tXmgYaOLj6tezLBxAimF3rkirbtyolTKAAt67du2Yr4N370cIFDHwDa8ygYQMHwYgpdvDwAUSIxJAhihhBosQFvZEzKxRhgYSJEyc0i07oebTpg6VPqxaYevXp1q5Hw46teTbtyLZvJ86tWzDv3nx\/A8crfLjd4sbhIk\/Odjlzs86ff40uPSv16lKvY49pIcRhhdqVnv8osRqFBhIWwJu4ayKFBhWqVVzQIEK9XRUeNGRwXSH\/CNLrwcXBB\/TRtoJ7gKEW4FssaNBCerSdoIEGKygIVwgaXNBBby5okAJmBIV3EwYegqibeRvAF+KCZbWnAXnDWdDgB9+xxqJX+GnwX3IcgHAehACIONOAGrwgnXwF2mhWgyAAyVx\/Oir5FYYpbnegBoAJCROJKcCwnUASUqilSy7GEJhTADwggQZzKWSADHRZhRBhKcxw41I57riXnD8BkMACCSnAJl1+AoUQDRrUYKZURBoZGFQP2BAnnAcRcAMOlKYpaUIN5lDjUkw6eVekk9KFlloIvUkoAFAhZIEOPzIrRaWKfMkp56kJqdqUoQjtsEGSQ3HppWAKjAWArrimmmmh4PGQ32NCweDeov+C3bqprsquiiaALvYQlAq\/6ikYqT4B9aeby7aKUGkxTAijTRb46Chkrao5aJppGYQtuQAKROewNb2gQZOZyXmQD6gmtG1CIlCLqAe0yjRCYRFDtjBBAfxA1kEGJ4RCaAM1eMGnL7Xb5ZcPfUxQvA6KypK0GlCLMkMqE9TBfPO2BG6UMztUM0FAPOsSyzn3vNDPBHXbksAEG90Q0gS1++JKE1fp9NMgH\/RvSiYDfPXRWR\/0cMUiwSzz1wpBbZDIJIO0M7Ro0xz2QSw\/OBLLLMTt89wH3VzkSALTqDfWDQWtAdweTQzx4IQ3pLRHJt\/J+EFqJyT1uxrBnODkYEO0tUb\/b3Pe+EMYLo4R3qKP\/pDAI2MUeNupG1T5Qha00LJFipMdu+x8N8QBzhVFvrvcFOWI+EOaD088RTDvB1HoyndeUQkTnq0Q6tFLX1EPHkp+0OvZa19R6UAwlHv44lfE+oaWd49++hTVPrDLAiX\/ftq9T\/S7BnkbBP39HsvfRHJEg4JgD4AB5EjzCAI+BCaQI9SLmUDOF5MABEEtCrhBwkYzO4twLwUmEN5MqKKmrkCkBx7wWlk6aJHSIWglHNjACNpmQSHwyiEr+AALyvcWFlpEYIdrSQdosIHNNcVYDrGAeSbExCY68YlQjKIUp0jFKlrxiljMohat2IIahUWDEOHA\/wg84C24+NAsK7iACNiXJgkM4GIOAQILQKC7rJzRKzL6wI0kAJRkRWQFbDTLHQmyMGwZxF5t6tjdrLcUNCFyVQV55LGQkjIBcoySABBUmyplLkAxizl86iRC+nSuT6qOKF2xFKYgORByIWtTyYHUtZbVylmaCpbLawi\/BGJIgiArX6wyIXBcSSk\/DuSXqFIX\/HKFSV7S8piUTBYcdWOraALTl9ZE1TQRMshMItGZrAQnvrR5w94UKynI1FcxgblNylmyIIrsZS1LJZB2xsZa9IykLetZzgfqEpfHeuZASOnJYCaHXwQdpSh9Ikz8QUSZ6Wzlmja5y+HUa6KmumYb71OlqXBy853wbGZBELYQe9JGkQQhqUJMWpBu8vMgGduYvkRqnG3G1E00dagDYeLSnYKkpz71CFCDypGhElUjRj0qRpKqVIswtakUeSpUJSLVqUKkqo1W3VtWTYLVrS7Tqx3pKlg\/OlaRiLWsLQUpWqOq1rVSta1uvSpc46pVum7krHHFq1v1ula+otWvZQXsWAULVsJ61bBbRWxWFWtVxk7VsVCFbFMlq1TKHtWyPgWCEk9gAR7atSIi6MHHRnC8z0YkaCwYgYZM20IPlZG18dsACGB7EQxUiLa4za1ud2uRgAAAOw==\" style=\"width: 192px; height: 162px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><i>y<\/i> = |<i>x<\/i> - 1|\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><i>y<\/i> = |<i>x<\/i>| - 1\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><i>y<\/i> = |<i>x<\/i>| + 1\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><i>y<\/i> = |<i>x<\/i> + 1|\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu5":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 4 and 5:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">The ratio of the rates of doing work of three persons, P, Q and R, is 5 : 4 : 3. If the three of them completed a job working together, and were paid a total of Rs.3000 for it, what would be Q&rsquo;s share? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.1000\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.1200\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.900\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>None of the above \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu6":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for question 6:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Ramu, with a given amount, can buy 20 erasers or 12 sharpeners or 5 pens. If he purchased an equal number of each of the three types of articles with thrice the given amount, find the number of pens purchased by him. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"9","CORRECT_ANSWER":"9","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu7":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 7 and 8:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">A cone has a base radius of 10 cm and a height of 7 cm. If a smaller cone of height 4 cm is cut away from the original cone by making a single cut parallel to its base, then what will be the ratio of the volume of the remaining part of the cone to the volume of the smaller cone that was cut away? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>343 : 64\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>263 : 48\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>279 : 64\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>343 : 48\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu8":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 7 and 8:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Two varieties of powder, costing Rs.240 per kg and Rs.160 per kg respectively, are mixed in certain ratios, to obtain two new varieties of powder, P and Q. Now, P and Q are mixed in the ratio 2 : 1 to obtain another variety R, which, in turn, is sold at Rs.247 per kg, earning a 30% profit. If P costs Rs.180 per kg, then in what ratio were the two initial varieties of powder mixed to obtain Q? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6 : 5\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5 : 3\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2 : 1\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3 : 5\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu9":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for question 9:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">What is the least natural number that should be added to 577, to make it a perfect square? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"48","CORRECT_ANSWER":"48","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu10":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 10 to 14:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Rakesh claims to sell sugar at cost price. However, due to his faulty weighing machine, he unknowingly gave 100 gm more for every 1 kg of sugar that he sold. Find the loss percentage incurred by him. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='42' Height= '33' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACkAAAAhCAYAAABEM4KbAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAQwSURBVFhH7ZZtTFtVGMdvkC+OZEARNjFrEcZkwBitkVbB+XUwkw1wvJnMRE3mh5HpBkuwVUBY4iIb5W1SOpANBoJ82pt+W0wIWQduDUxYwhhgAIGqHSCsSMvfc58eYAQx6eWiH7ZfcpLn5dx7\/nnuc865AmSktbUFBsNn3JMP2UT29fVi27YgxMVpeUQ+NizS4XDAVF0NQRBovP5GPM\/Ix4ZFtnzbTOL0BgM0ajWi98TwjHxsWGR\/fz86O7vI1sa9hoiISLLlRNaN86pGjd27o7gnH89EysXTJ1KjjvVo4ywsLLDh5N5qZmZm4HS6c8siz5z5EjqdDgkJCaisOs+jnhHxyi4olSHc+3dKSr6CSqVCaGgozpWW8qib4qIiaLVazM3NkS84nQv48IP36aw7dCgZ7x05QnZaWjpN8ISOjg60t7dzb32s1ru0RkVlFWpMJrK7un6inG1yknyTyUy+iHDj+nUKnjiZw0NAw6WLFLvGcptB9dfn6f0iLvZJRTu\/oJD87GPHsH37i1hcJJcQTuXm0qTe3j4eAqampuDt7Y3MzHd5RF6WqicKcbncIs+VGjE\/7yD7m\/qLfKYb4XRxESV6eu7xEDDJSv6clxf7\/Ck8Ii\/37\/fRmnq9AYUF+WT\/YX+EnJMnWJ+u7WnBYrlFk\/bvT8Qsa9RFlwuffHycYukZWXya\/HzX2oq9MTFQs\/v+ypWr+HVslNa8efNH+pIVFeWsL2tYtRfdu7u8rIwm+Pr64aXgYHbWRcJ361Ykp6xUUvzbGRsbkzwmJiZowfU4\/E4qYmPVZO8KD0dY2E4EMy0pKakrR1B3dzeMRiPq6uowPT0NhcIfh9MyeBZoa2tDOHtY6tBoNBgdHeVvW83g4EMqkuV2J6twC9n2R1P0jyrawsjICCttBR4\/dvBHAMstdwvUmC\/wCFhTz1M1pA6bzbZuJd8+kIS9vIrHs7Ph768g+y+2ZoBCAaH353skKD09g26A8fFxut6e37KFXrzZ3LZYaP2lc\/KCuYZ822+\/o4d9XaqkmBCbVHQCAgLo6PH188ON73+ghzYT8drbEx2Fffve4hHgT3Yd6thts0OpRFBQIDKzslZ68u6dOzCbzWhsvExH0H+B2EL19fUYHv6FR9zMzc6itrYWDQ2N5C+LlMJHR4\/iclMT99Zy9mwJ8vI+5Z50JIs8lZtDLZKXp+eR1TQ3N1E+TqvjEel4LHJoaAip7PykhmajuPg0z7ix2+0w6PXL+cSkAzwjHY9FJh88iBcCA6lnvNjVWVD4Bc+4KS8zkrjKqiqE7wxbtSmk4rFIq9VKh\/0MG6KYpb+XJQYePMDAwEOyXw5RIT4+geyNILknhwYH\/1Hkk4SolOwn+k3uSUeyyGHWm89EPsHTIfLz\/AIeWYtKueP\/3TjiHevj44NSYxmPrCU6KhKJiUnckwrwN633DZOVKm\/aAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='37' Height= '34' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACUAAAAiCAYAAADYmxC7AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAASJSURBVFhH7ZZdTFxFFMeXXQpYBMrSAgkLCFuxtUqVJnyY+iAYaNA+FNAtfSFRKZYq7NoGTZoKdRch0EQtKRZKBbvALj4UtKGlEaU+LLQUAihYl76QQIN8E\/kUgb9zzw4oQnX3LqYv\/SWTnHNm7sw\/d86cGQk2gWv19UhLS8Ps7CyP2IfdosZGR7FTqcRW18d5xH5Ei1paWkJ1VRUcHBwgkUiwfYc3JiYnea99iBZ1qayMxCQfOYJnn9mDx7a6PnxRjY2NqK2tIzsqMgIyxy0PX9Tf2Rf2PBy3OD0S9Z88EmUt\/5uo+wMDqKiowLlzRWhubuFR61AGB1F5GJ+Y4JH1VOr1SEpKQlZW1rrKbzQYoNG8h8XFRfJJVO2VK3BxcaGJV9o772bQAGvIzdXhWHo6Zh5wzZRdLKU5U1NT4eUlR2zcASq+AoJAB9anVmvIF5D09prh4e4GH19fVnu+w+DgINKOHqVJzhcX82H2sefp3YiKeoFsQ3U1zd3R2UX+6VOn4OzsjOnpGfIFJJ8Xn6dBBmMND1lQ+PnhqV278Qf\/pfbgr\/DDG2++RXbbnVZa705bO6amfiO7oPAs9a0g+ehMDnWYzb08ZCEqIoLi4+MPzhNriYwIR0jILrI\/+\/QTy7ws\/05oNPDx8cUy9fyFpFJ\/mQZptToeAn5lW+jOttSV3fwT\/5K81nKjoYHWCA8Ph6NMhqz3P2DbNU2xqioDjRkZGVnNSckkWzSS\/5X048dRUFAAhUJBvqdcvimiBDo7OpCfn4+amq\/ITz\/2NlvHn+zk5MOQs7WEdY0sjej0jbI3UXx8PAlxZBdrplqNhEOHIJXKVrevv78fKpUKiYmJVjWtVkvfbUSv2UxrXW+4gfIvLpFtMplwJiebPYWka4un8FempqbIDg56AgEBgauJLgjPy8uDTqezqhmNRvpuIw6++gr8AwLIVr3+GoKClWT\/3NNDAqkk7AsLQ0npReoQuHr1G+q0pVZZS093N839LSs\/AkkJCetFDQ8PQ6kMJicnJ4e1bLI9PLahr6+PBm8mL8dEIzR0L\/eAQpbDwnomU7Nl+6R8+wZYvsTFxVpUshYbG4eurh\/po82kp\/sndqJd8X1TE48Ac+zEpaSkrE\/0FYScsuW0zc\/Ps4MwjuXlf1aajRHydWxsjHtrEUrCyp24RpS1zMzM4OTJE5B7etKfDQwMRDm7zDcLEaKWkXxYRWL2738RZwsL8dzeUPL1+ko+xj5sFnXvXi8JeCk6hkfYNs7NIeTJnXRlLCws8Kh4bBZ1\/Vo9iar48jKPWNCoMyne2WW5\/e3BZlE\/3GyixXW5H\/OIhaTEBIq3tNziEfHYLEo4nd7eO+Dk5Iy6uq\/pNJVcuECChHbrdisfKR4RiQ7cZHXGw919VYggMCY6mmyTjU\/pjRAlSmCa1Zzy8nIUFRVhYOA+sj88TaLu3v2FjxCPzaKE01VaWrIudwLZBSv32s4K6u88Ih6bRQmFUyZ1oC1ra2\/H0NAQe9On0l\/S6XL5KPsQtX2trbfZ0yYIMpkj3Nzc2LtLioyMTN5rL8CfXd5yRlpObMIAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>10%\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='47' Height= '34' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAC8AAAAiCAYAAADPuYByAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAQ0SURBVFhH7Zd7TFNXHMcbeblQkMcSyHTZBi1k7CFYYOiWArIlZCyZCqiwuVemlalFMju3P8jwH1NqwiiFZOLocBoSl8VFlghLyMCptQ9hTtmIj\/0Dsdsqlo1XSnh8d++vpwVtlabcm8yET3Jzf+f3O7nn09tzzr1XApGZnZ2FWq3G8ePfsIxwiC7\/2acHIZFIsL\/qY5YRDtHkf71yBRnp6STOHxUVe1hFOESRn5ubg1wmQ7JMjoaGBpJXqSpYVThEkefneVdXF6anp3Hj+vVHS34hFov50ZW3Wi3L8v5Yln8YYsjzuxnPPfLGlhbU6nSs5cuUywWNRoOLJhPLLI7JdIHky8t3sMyDmZmZwaGaGigUCmzevAV2+5+s4uaIrhbbt5dRPx6v\/PnzP9MgyclylvFl756PqI++wcAyi2O326HVatHZ+SPLPBjt4cN0fZ3uCFLkcqxdmw6Xa4pqTuddqmlr52+uhN+TT544QQX+2PDyK6w0Dy9QVPS6t0\/zsa9YRVhSZMkoePU1in9oP0Nj2S5fprZq54eIi4unZ4cHiebAAepUVlYOqTQSmVnZrORmdHQU0VFRiI2Nw9bSUlHln1yzGu+9\/wHFNrZWevt+gePvvyg2ft1KNQ+SFm6e9\/Sco0ZEeDgyFJkUexgeHkZ1dTV3vovvvj0lqvzG\/Dw8sXoNLchDNZ\/TWOPj43j3nR2Qca8a9+Od8\/+OjCAsNBTr7pNfSPPRL0WVt5jNiJJKkZSUhJAVK1D3RT3u3HHQmGc7OqlPf\/81DA0NUeyV\/ycA+WPNR0WV5+HF2trauA3kArXLtm3Ds2lpmOPWZj73z6xaFcPN\/TjaNJYkPzAwgIKCAiiVyqAPvV5P1\/JHX18vjXfRdAkGfT3FN27eRJOBE+fiJcnz66G1tRVGozHow2Kx0LX8kZerRFracxRvLS2BTJ5C8e+\/9S9dXkxsNiuNdcns\/nElxVvw1NPPUOwjP+J0UkKeksoyvjQa3B8WhsYmlhGP7KxM5KzfwFpAU6N7qpxpb0dVZSVWrnxsXn58bAxvFBVh7z41y\/jS0XEWhYWF3Nm98sXi2tWrSExMhJnddR7+4VRVtZ\/yqamp5OCVF5LBwUG4ptyPdX+McTfq9m07a\/kyOTnJvRa4WOte+JoHweXr6+oQERHBzVn3Y90fL77wPBSZWawVPILKN7MFzR8Wi5Vl53Fy62rTpjepnv1SDssGjyDyvFRJcTFJRUdH09lqtbGqm+7un5CQkEC18LAw5OSsZ5XgEUT+XE834uMfx+nT36NSvc+v\/NtvlUOZm4ve3j5IIyMfuiUHiiDy\/JvnxMQExRW7VX7lHQ4HnWe4XSM0JOT\/I7+Q3apdfuU9BPIwDJRl+YUsyweI4PKqXTsXlec\/NDLWKVgmeASXP\/iJhvsWluLWrT9YxpfYmBjk5W9krWAB\/gNCDZnW01mxjwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu11":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 10 to 14:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Find the sum of the first 20 terms of the series 3, 4, 6, 9, 13, 18, &hellip;&hellip;&hellip; <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1890\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1600\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1504\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1390\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu12":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 10 to 14:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Ram and Shyam have some coins. If Ram gives <i>x<\/i> coins to Shyam, he would have thrice as many coins as Shyam would. If Ram gives 2<i>x<\/i> coins to Shyam, he would have twice as many coins as Shyam would. What is the ratio of the number of coins with Ram and Shyam initially? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>7 : 1\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5 : 2\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5 :1\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Cannot be determined.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu13":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 10 to 14:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">In a race, Mohan beats Sohan by 24 m and Sohan beats Rohan by 100 m. If Mohan beats Rohan by 120 m, find the length of the race. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>720 m\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1000 m\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>600 m\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1200 m<b> <\/b><b>\r\n<\/b><\/font><b>\r\n<\/b><\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu14":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 10 to 14:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">If <i>K<\/i> = <\/font><font style=\"font-family:;\"> <img height=\"43\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAHMAAAArCAYAAABLnrd8AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAArQSURBVHhe7ZwJWI3bGscjUmkgoXIepzgNyEXlSKguOXLJlItuxWlOca4cQ3co5zE3qHQQOU6DMs9DDppQos5jOIYyRKWBlFKZKt671rvX3rWH0hX5OvbvedZjv+9a+2uv7\/99a71rfe9HBiRw+vRvEBUVzSwpXOXA\/v0QG7uTWQASxRwzegxcvpzJLClc5VFBPhgaGsKr16\/RFhMzNiYajI1NmCWF60ydYgM+i3\/Ez2Jijvj2W1i6dBmzpHCdnbExoKGhiZ+FxCwqKoSOHTuSOfMM87yfsrIySExMJMPyZeZpO7KysqC8\/Bmz2pYrV65gv0tKHjPPp+fevXtQUVHJLB55Dx+CjIwM3L13X1jMfXv3YMXDh3nM0zy7d++Cbt26gYGBAaioqMCkSZPhNRu\/PzW74uPxtx49dpx52oYXL2pgvJUVqKurg76+PqioqsLhw0dY7afj5MkToKCgAGnpF5mHBz3fKsrKsHFjuLCYC7y9oEuXLlBTU8M8TfPq1SuQJ22dnF3QvpOTgyd3+y870L59+zYp2fj57du3kJqaCsXFJWi3lpzsbJCV7Yh\/LyHhFPO2DZt+\/hn\/7j1yJ1DmOjqSC7o71NfXw5s3b+DChQuCCzqHnJPz58+T\/r9D+0Ogx1zs4wPy8vLQoUMHyMz6ndU0MHDAAJg6bbqwmBbm5qCnp8+s5qmrq4P09HRypb4Q2LSTcfG70I6JioLOnTtjvZurC2hp9SFiFmNda6itfQO6ut\/AzJkzoXOnTnDs+AlW0zbk5ubC9evXmQXw73\/5Qm8yZ7179w5P\/Fd9+oD\/ip\/I8FuM5yMwMAjrPpTKigrw9vaGM6dPg5qaGjnnwncmZabtDNDW6dcgZn19HfTT0QZ9gwHMw7uyMjIy4OLFi4KSmZkJtUQ4UabY2IDpSDMiaj3atAPDh5uAmZkZGQZU4Nat2+hvLfb\/sIPpM2zhJblI6Mk6m5TMaj4e+fl5sGPHDggPD4ekpCTmFef3rEzoJCsrNNQfPHAAh2BdXV2Y970T87aely9fgKKiokQxXV1coGtXpQYxK549A1kS\/IyzGo92LbnKtL\/uiydMqHToCKVPn2IbyvPKSjA3HwMjTE3h+fMq5uURuW0rfudQM3PKqVMJsHz5crFy7tx51qKBmOgoPN7BQ4fI\/L4XP69ctQqeNvo9reXokcMgR0YUQX9JsbGZQk7mS9aCRyyJInv06AGRkduZpwFlpa6gp2\/ALHFqqqthhb+\/WJ9Xr17TZMzx9GkpEayrRDHdXF15v5XZRIjn6ODPgbn3SXREbHsHhybvzIcPHsBgsmhdsGAh2o0pLi4CHW1tPMaGkFDmFYcKcffuXbHyjFxcooSGbIARI0aAiYkJBh\/02Do6OmSeSmMtWkdRYSEeU71nL0hLS8dI3d\/fD32BQcGsFcCqlStxOrpx4ybzNLBu3Vpsr9XnK6iqqmZeYej8ep+cX9E+5+Y+wPhCEs2JuSE4CP+mQMzCwkfo4A8NR48cQTslJRVtUWiQpNG7N3SWk4OwsDDSiXXkyloN165dRyG+7tsXZv59FmzetAmPk5fXsgi5pdwnYTo97pGjx5in9RQUFICvry8ZSQ4zD4kFamuFzks0iQWoPXfePAgNDcU+h5OgiIqwNSIC6xISEkC9hxp87+TSqvmyMU+ePMZjp6aeY54GtkduwzqBmDk52ejg35l+\/\/0PdCIBxvr162Hu3Lng5OQEe\/fuwzpK4aNH4OzsDK7kFqfBiK2tLZZzJHpLTUnBOv6Q4ebmJvFHtIbS0lLw8PCAP27cYB5xaGQZExPLrAZCQkLgAVmfNQcVkd49\/\/zhB1Aly6\/k5BT0U8Hc3d3B3t5e0GcvLy8c2Tw9PWFnXDy2O3ToII5Y\/BiitVRXV8HChQvJb8plnga2beVdRA3DbBVvmHV2cUXbatxYtOlSpX\/\/\/hgWU9tzvhfWtwfoEoYOw5u3RDAPgNd8Txg1ajSUl5czj2Tc+fMQKfYOjszLTcTuTBoAdSCOyTZT0Y769VdYtGiRYAOBdv5v1tb4pcRmIjyuQacPGlnGkyWTv58fmFtYtuhu+e3UKThAIlN3MqrQPn\/MyPRjE7IhWFhMehurqqjAwEGGzCNOBgmA6JeWLGlfe7dVLLjTIWuxD8HSwgK\/\/76h+XPh6uKMU6JATIrhoIFgOPgvOGkfISE63XtszNWrV7BTy5b5Mk\/74MfFPjBt2jSwtLSEbZGRzCtOGYms4+PiyGgkLBp\/yL158xbzcAsqZnc1NWExbWdMB02tPuQurQZZMkcqKnYlUVQpqwWYM3sWdiqd3KHtgVoSxHh4uJOh1QLt0idPcP4PCQ3DOlHS0y5g\/yaTdSWfkpIS0NLUhG7d1ch5ef825+dgovUEGDrMSFjMoMAA7EwdWQdt3sTbg1RSUobZs2fDoIED0fbwnM9ac5\/jx47B+PHfkXVdw9qNbrMNHz4csiTscdItSXs7O+znMCMjmDVrFm5JUrtxJM81vunXj6weXITFvJSRgT\/8+vU\/0KZpCWPHjsWrmUaAoWQ92Z6ge6VN0dTinBJAlmNDhw7Ffk8lw3MyWWpxFbr3raAgD\/G7dguLSXcm6EZARMQ25pHCdW7duglycnJQVlYuLCbF22s+bmRLaR9sDAslU4IxfhYT8zZRumfPnrijIYX7\/JVE6BERW\/GzmJgUuzlzwM\/Pn1lSuAqNvg0NBwsic4liUqwnWENhYSGzpHAR2xkz8MEGH5k4skjmbxjzyxxyZ9JUBLqvKVonLdwodHnVq1cvcHR0RJsuo2RSSNhNH+OIlg0hIRAcHCyxTlo+fwkICMBHj3x77dq1TQ+zUtofUjFbCH0YHxgYgEOau7sH5rByDamYLaC+rh7MRpqCqqoqifL9YKSpKVm+9WrTBOiW8KcTs7KyAtzcXOF+Lu+J\/NIlSyBsY3ir0jfoBj3d3qN5QRR+ZmAcyyrgCn86MemWpNGwoSS6mwNbNvPyj65evcZqPw5HDx8GWVnZFmf+txWcFLOkuBhGmZlBVHQM8\/Cgj6M8PTzAwcEB7OzsBEX0AcDdO3cwQVpeQUGQuyMKnQNFs+NoKSoqYi0kk5ychNnlXHx\/lXNi0hRN\/uO2NWvWMi+P\/fv3oZ9mdtMnGvzi5b2AteBRWvoE2303wZp5xKEJ3qJ5q7REi1xAjQnfGAbKSsrkdxxgHm7BGTHpnLZ3z25QUVFGIWgJapSrSvFdvgz9efkFzCMOzfzW19MDIyNjTEaTlNv6Ify0wh80NDQEjwe5CGfErKmphq6KiphrGxYaiqI1TjymWFqYg6amFn6urKwUy\/6mz\/asxo0DfQMD3K80NjKCseOsoLWZq\/QlKPp76AMI+rrFkCFDsPw\/rz62BZwRk558\/tot4eRJMTFpPX3WSl8s1dPTxXr6GqGPz2J4yyJV+grB2bNnoaqK95oEzSpIS0sjdz2aHwzNuqfZ\/PSNrjNnzgjK48fSpcl7oRkOomIW5OfjE3UlZWVY5OOD2eRjRo\/Gdl5e3qzVl027EZNmmGdnZ+MrBI0xMTbCth\/jdcH2TrsRsylWr1qJbbmcp9NWtBsxL1+6hHmvx0+cZB4e9EVT2ja\/mQj3S4GTYu7fx1tPBgQGMQ8Vk5c5qK2tg\/8ZBg1KIiK2oG\/ixEms1ZcNJ8VMSkwEJSUliNz+C\/Pw2LN7F1keqKOAdNOb\/jt5sg2r\/dIB+B9N\/\/nYLYIQhQAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"115\" \/> ,<\/font><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"> where <i>x<\/i> is an integer and <i>K<\/i> is divisible by 25, but not by 125, then <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><i>K<\/i> is divisible by 81, but not by 243.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><i>K<\/i> is divisible by 27, but not by 81.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><i>K<\/i> is divisible by 243, but not by 729.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><i>K<\/i> is divisible by 729, but not by 2187.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu15":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for question 15:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">How many four-letter words can be formed by using the letters of the word LINGAA? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"192","CORRECT_ANSWER":"192","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu16":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 16 to 21:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">What is the sum of the first ten terms of an arithmetic progression whose first term is <i>a<\/i> and common difference is half the first term? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>25<i>a<\/i>\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>32.5<i>a<\/i><i>\r\n<\/i><\/font><i>\r\n<\/i><\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>42.5<i>a<\/i>\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>50<i>a<\/i>\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu17":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 16 to 21:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">If a sum of Rs.24,000 is lent at 10% per annum, compound interest, compounded annually, for five years, what is the interest accumulated during the first three years? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.7944\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.7692\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.7200\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>None of the above \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu18":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 16 to 21:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Ramu has four sons. The product of their ages (in years), which are all integers, is 225. Even if the sum of their ages is known, their individual ages cannot be found. What is the age of the youngest son? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1 year\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2 years\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3 years\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Cannot be determined\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu19":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 16 to 21:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">In the given figure, PT and PR are two tangents of the circle with centre O. If the measure of the angle PRT is 36&deg;, then find the measure of the angle TOR. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhFwGPAPcAAP\/\/\/5+fn\/f390hISO\/v7zg4OLe3t9\/f3zAwMM\/Pz0BAQOfn51BQUI+Pj2BgYHBwcFhYWKenp9fX139\/f2hoaJeXl6+vr8fHx7+\/vxAQEAAAABgYGIeHh3h4eCgoKCAgIJA6AAA6kNv\/\/\/\/bkDoAZrb\/\/6ysrC4uLnR0dCUlJSMjI7GxsZWVlRQUFBISEsHBwU1NTRwcHDExMS0tLQYGBkRERCYmJioqKjo6OjQ0NEZGRggICP\/\/tmYAAGa2\/\/+2ZgBmttuQOjqQ2\/\/\/22YAOpDb\/7ZmAGYAZgAAZgAAOrZmZpBmAEQtEwAnYicXABYWFhoaGh8fH0tLS7m5uTw8PCwsLB4eHgQEBAoKCj8\/P2tra3d3d7Ozs6GhoUdHR1dXV19fXzoAAJA6OgAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAFwGPAAAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypxJs6bNmzhz6tzJs6fPn0CDCh1KNGSAokiTChUw4KjSp1BvEihgIKrVqy8PIEiAtatXkwkKHPhKtmxHAwoWmF3LlmIABgTayp27sIEDAXTz6hX44MHev3IFQGgAuLBZAgwiGF7sdYGCqowjR5VQgKvky0nDjsXMeaiBAnE7i\/4ZYADe0ah3TnCQunVOChNcy6YpgEGF2bhhElBgIbdvlgcUXPhNHGUCBZaLKxeJQcHm5dA9WhgQ+iCG6xOyT4hwXW307wcrMM04LfBAAAcKMmhQwF77BAjsN2goMIDDcPDRO1AYiIGChw8OBIBBdQpdYEAHBWTAQAAE4oebAxwAIEEHHyhQgQQWEWCBAxtAAJmDhYGgwYgjhiDCQUwFsIADHnDwXEYCRDAAAh+C+NcIJJSQ0FQmUOgUSAkMgJyNN+aI0AEnoPABB+QxhwADLxLZFo46GpRACio80CBJFnzwgHdSskWlQStsAGVLDVQWpphGEsRCCyzAdEABva1Z1pgDoeDCCzLVFqGdX+EJAAwxRAlTBxA0\/wloVGMKIMMMW8YUQVqLekUADTXodIFYlV61gA0x\/IhTWIp2WpQEN+CwwgA8WcCAqUolIMMNBAiwQaQ1cdABrEUZkEMOGAIQYE8QKMZrUKXp8KEBrPIkgHDH\/rTaA4QNZCuuNS3AabQ7wbapQcP25Cq3OdV221YGMfsTuuTWtFtv4xp0rU\/NtUtTcPexC66oOzFQp70vHWdZA34hpK5PCSAA8EvNbSbAB2DKe+tPxS7M0nTVEbxQuD0t8EGpFo8kHnkPR3zQwT5RcFvIJulXUAQQMDSvT9+yTBKEBvnbEMc9fWCozRulaJDHIKfbrE\/ZAf3RVDUOdJ5DM\/eUsNIdaf+VXEE8b8zvThlgS3VEmiW0gckKodxT1l9PhBbZA039UNQ8PZ12RW95XcF+EKGdkwQezE2RXUUPRG1EZu8kwA5+S9RXQzpDBPdOPicO9WAOeRBs3ltDxEMPGvhQ0gBNS34QYsY2tEPgCRUe0Q8jAlGSyqIr5FjoCR0+0eOac+45SUnHfhBlVzN0wAcU6X2Trr4btOnPCg1Pkeo4yZ28QGh5jVC9t08cN2vTA1Aa6glhP5HxDAVBohAkSe\/7ahU5\/\/zREAVhIgBDgOC6SOqL7kBs7RNPEe4LERQPiFAEkSAvdrXJnOMQVxHyIeQH9xuIEdAXkt5J7l0ZOV1FoKeQIERmUCBBoCBIYCe5Od0HI5arCAATAsGCTFAkoJPccS6HkcYVT4EI4cERqgSAARYwJJHzW8M40oE\/vS8i8jtR\/T7oEdv5TUbWk0j+IrJCFp5vJG5LWwUS5RH3NRCHMNFY2lwGkiAeESc2\/wSaAHAWEgfKTHs26RrVEjiSKUbEjSzJos2YRhICbAB8C+HgS4qoNKuZpGIqhONMzBiyhDHvI\/H6Yk3EF7LqoaRkFhEkS\/DIq7qpRIz\/U+RLJIAAQMKKA3dZCSZBOCIkVGlzGkhCAeungftx0iRpBNgDdtUSmAnkB64EgAcF8sIfmOgHnlOCjjRpHIVZTDDVcom+BEIlQdFPRPerIkpiuDACDKB0LokkCF1nzCXE8of7gok42+UYDMxEAe4EAOuCyTrPGfNERoPJNMkFPJro0QjkDKYPUSTKlKyTW8uzCSF\/6boxDfQgt\/zInNjGK0vehAlNEEH90LdRYc7vZPC7pP+a7PW9nBDACa0bCCyDiRBthiSX0WLfTrQSRYiCESQLbdf+6GUaiTBTOq9qFx1\/cjeJuJQjpGoXBoNCgYJhziQJJZcJidIA6kDkpxkJAKXINUOkfIaGCsGADp5QU4s8IJXkGmJSKBPPhFyAPRiIqES8GU1uQREqu6lrQbQaT6xOhDK0g9UWTQmUBzAgeAA4K8kKehEBcKAAYD0WGbFiAQQ4AEwP4B9B5MqQCnygA2UN0xqN6JUAfJYAvsxnRizgAQpQ1FRDLYtjoRCFSB11IRgoAAMieyw+tkUKMPBSZDk7EAJUoADQApgh2zK1BTTAAy06oV8HYh4IZIACJ7SXI+f\/MriBTChBDODAFFpgPQJgIAD+ARA4HdQB9rj3vfCN7wkyQIX42ve++M2vfvfL3\/4i4L5UqIIVMnAFDWAhAwguQBb+84EPaGAHH0CAFLTgngpb+MIYzrCGN8zhDnv4wxZmEkMkcJ0Sm\/jEJ94CFbiA4ha7+MUwjrGMZ0xjGkeAC11ogI69kIUvgOHHIA6ykIdM5CJ\/WK8bQSVh5TKCMJCoc8nbJQCa\/GQR7gVP1pwbNKnZpvrt7spdFgM65+bN0gkqhIDBcpvm1k6C4GlzX9YLlUkU56\/1081OvmKajfRCv0XVzWs2zJi8PDeLFiTLe64SMHkItJIeBNFFqtISqSZTBIRAunsvctkppjsT201fZqmevsxUQ32ZrpJaMmo9dWQGpOpWu\/rVsI61rGdN61rb+tY6CQgAOw==\" style=\"width: 279px; height: 143px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>144\u00b0\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>72\u00b0\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>108\u00b0\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>90\u00b0\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu20":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 16 to 21:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">If <i>f<\/i><i> <\/i>(<i>x<\/i>) = <i>a<\/i><i>x<\/i><sup>2<\/sup> + <i>b<\/i><i>x<\/i> + <i>c<\/i>, where <i>a<\/i>, <i>b<\/i>, and <i>c<\/i> are positive integers, and <i>f<\/i><i> <\/i>(0) = 2, <i>f<\/i><i> <\/i>(1) = 10, and <i>f<\/i><i> <\/i>(2) = 28, find the value of <i>x<\/i> for which <i>f<\/i><i> <\/i>(<i>x<\/i>) is minimum. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>-0.3\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>-0.6\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>0.3\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>0.6\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu21":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 16 to 21:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">If four men and two women can do a work in 48 days, while two men and four women can do the same work in 64 days, how long will it take 12 men to complete a work, which eight women take 12 days to complete? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='59' Height= '35' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAADsAAAAjCAYAAAAqoHJFAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAZmSURBVGhD1VlpUJVVGEZAUQxQwJviACngSpRbIwoNkrKoiZZoggiTEokb+ieaSQHBsh+aIpnkNGWojbJviWYjkrKMCsjiAojsKKCAgqAsT+e897BcZexex2uXZ+bMPed53+8733PP+73vOfeqQQF0dXbi6NGj8PHxoXbixElhGRxQSKyXpyfU1NQwefIUWFpaUv\/z9RuEVfUht9jg3UEkzs9vOzo6OonbvMmXuNORUTRWdcgtNjEhAVu3bEXzo0eCAW4UFpDYgMAgwag2FArj\/nj48CE81rqT2EuXLgtWtaGw2LYnTzBvnjU0NNRJ6Lff7RUW1YfCYltbWxAQEIBA1kxNTWFkNB5nz54TVtXGK4cxR2VFBfT0dDF27Di0tLQKVnUht9iamhrk5OSIUR+cHB0onMvKywWjupBbrLOjI4m6e7dMMEDHs2d4x9QEo\/UNBt\/KtrW1ISsri9XRDsH0IfL0KRI7Y8ZMJCcns\/f0LOztFxAXErJHeCmO6uoqZGZm4gHL7sqGjNglixfTwzc0NAhGFj\/s34+RI0eSD2+amposWQWiu7tbeCiO3UGBdK\/IqGjBKA8k9unTp1jn4UGT6umNxoMHD8g4EHh9zcjIoHb\/\/n3Bvjr2hATTvNExsYJRHtSSk5JgNnGiVKiuLnR19V4q9nWgpLgY6enpaGpqxqHQgzR3TGycsEpRUlJCPhkZmWhsbBQsUF9fT9c9j0ePmmW+\/NLSUro+Nze3N\/LU+Oll\/nwbFBQU4kNbW6irayhNbH19HVYsX07i6MsdNQq2NjYyK1uQnw9r67m9PryN1tfHcXHCcnJwoFLX0ND3jJWVFZBIxmDL1m3o6uqCy7JlMtdPmTIV1\/PyoNba2pdFZ8+apVSxq1etosk3+voiNTUVO3Zs732gxKRkep20R4ygcXh4OK1MREQEDA0MoKU1nG1oWvH7sWNkP3HyD3FXIPTgAeLy8gtwOCyM+vv27ceVK1foSMrH770\/QzZBzZk9W2liqyoraVJ7+4WCkWKT70biExKTmNh2+Pv7Iz4+QVilcF\/zGfkUF5fgMTuI8K2q8+IlwsoXaSYkb4+lvpvwTU29SGOO9PTLSElJ+W+xPDPfu3dP7jZQ2eI4m3KGHuL5vXTKGSkfFR0jGCA7O5utzD6sdXeHlZUVhg7VJJ+CwkKyr\/z0EyZYk9X2FlRVSb\/Eb3buIlsKm2fIkCHESSQSuLq6UpnkeKlYXnft7OwwYcIEuZqZmRk96ECIiYqiB9i793vBSPHXuXPEx7HV7Gbv2+pVrjTmzdjYmEXCR5hkYUHjHrEJ8XE0PnU6EmEiweXl5ZONo6zsLry9vWFiYtJ7LydnVlaFnaDMleWJh0+6ztNLMFIc\/Tmc+NSLafgzOYn6X270Zcmsr9av81hLfI9YvgiSMWMw13oerN61xLTplr0Z98KFC4iLi6c+x61bt9hRVHr9G3tneZacPm0qTdpzSiq6fRsTWURw7h92Jv5FJJOg3cFk5zhx\/DiGss0L52\/evCVYYOvmzVIBrB0K+1GwgP0CO+L6C96x3U\/qK8YEC3NzInktUwZycrJhYKBPcxgbS0NM5y0d+oyNjUdzUxPGGxnReNy4cTA0NKS+ZIyEPiMijos7AdeuXoWGujp7n4fJHEKys69hlJ4e+fMw5pmc9z1ZRMmIjYmOppTf3t4umNcPXux37dwJNzc3HDhwEDdu3MCRI0dw504p2cvLyxAUFAR3lpx8WYnKzMxCbW0t+fB+D3ik6OjoYOEiB8H0obysDCHBwTSHl5cXIsVvZDJi\/wuVrHzwTTuvf\/1bUVGR8HhzSEpMoBWLUmBPrZBY7w3raYLnm8vyFcJD+fj7\/Hm4uLiw3KIOc4tJCkWhQmLnzJ5Fe+e0tLT\/bWWvX8+FOcstzqyU8C2uIpBbbMvjx2wrNxyLHBwFM\/ggt9jc3BwKWT+\/HSxzxiA0NBRJ7MTU2dklPFQfcos99tuvL7yrvNnY2KKWbSYGA+QW+9Phw7TX\/Mr\/a1RXV6Ourg4h4uC9dOnHVApUHQolqIEy3wdz5pDgmppawaguFBLb\/+zbA2cn6a+O5eUVglFdyC3Wbc0a6Ovrv7Bvtpw+DcOGaaGxsUkwqgu5xQYFBtAKrlzpipKSO+wcWYXtftIN9uYt24SXakOhMOb\/x\/JfCbS0tKCtrU1Cvb\/wEVZVB\/AvlyTvmG1QfFkAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>   \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='57' Height= '34' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAADkAAAAiCAYAAADlCXHdAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAX0SURBVFhH3VhpTJRHGF4ur7qLEEFZbCISroJSUYGK0EATjYAkrdiEBcUmUkRbIRYEtKmg\/sDUKqbgxaFGaRG0XE2RahCktuoPq1UbDxAqlrqc9QLk8OnMu7O4NA1+WJZseJLJzjzvzDfzfPO+M+9+Mrwm8o4fR3R0NJqa\/hKM4eK1RDbevw8rKyvIZLKxKbK7uwtvubiQQF5u3vxdWAwXwxYZszYakyfL4bto0dgUWfTdKRJWea4KGz79ZOyJbFarYWZmilWrIqmtCgsbWyL7+\/vxXoA\/nJxdBAOsjowkkWPm4PkmL48EzZs\/HzExMVizZg3s7e2JCw0NReHJU6KnYUKSyKNHjmD27NkkbPr06VQmTJhAIqdOnYpt23eInoaJYR08utDG5K1btwVjuBgkMivrEHZ9uUu0hkZwUBCJvHHjpmCGj\/LyH5CQkID29g7B6AcDIs9XV9GinZxeHi5DobSkBGlpaWhpaRXM8BEXu4HmrKu7Jxj9QMZPzmPHjtFkvPj6vStM+kfK1i9ozoaGPwSjH8gS4uNporAwFd6YNAne3guFaeRx+dIlrIyIgJeXF1JStyF2g2Yn6+sbyN7d3Y2MjAwsWbIEnp6eWLo0EDk5uWRrbm4m1+aJiC5OnizEpk2JVK+9exdRUVE0dvHixUhPTydelpOTg6rqarx48QJmpqbwXOBNhpHGzxcuYNw4MxLl4+OD8ePGU92M\/TY++BM9z5\/Diy2Oc25ubvD396f18HZGZia6urqo7v62h3giu7\/7+mCukGOBpzcePnyIadOsqQ8fO3PmTKqvjVn3Mibb2tpgYmzM3oJ+RHp5LoCRkTGuXPmV2nV1tVDa2MDY2ARqdTMeNDbSNZWYlEx2jo6OdpZlmSEoeBm1N8bF0cIbWV+Oixd\/ofb5mp9QcCKf6sXsrNAiXKVCMBs7KiLV7C0bGRkhMChYMBqkpmylhWndVYu21lZ2at9Afv63tPvLQ1cQ\/9u1a9Q\/I3MftT9aHUkvoa+vHzXMG7lt1ix75tabUFFRgWfPnlG\/IUVev34dAQEB8PPzk1S46\/8X6mpraQE8DnVRWlKsEdmgEXmcHYBz2G5yTreEqcLJzkPqzRm28FnkS3VzhQLBy0LIxrGXxaCFhcXAOEtLS2RlZw8tkgf7EZbt5ObmSipXr14VIweDuyKfVBUeIRgN0vfsJr6942\/U1JynuiuLx7SdO1FUVIQ7t2\/TYRi64kMxAticnAQTExOWhR2l\/gUFhcKiAY\/d8vJyJCYmwk7E5ai4K3\/rfIfkcsWg62Kex1xaRGdXNz7fsoXq56qqhRU4w1yOc7pufvfOHVqntbU1bGyUePLkCfH792XC2dl50J17mL34QSJbWRxwwsXFVTAji7LSUnr+lCkWiGfXlsdcjUBe+E5+X1ZGdVvbGUhKSkJISMiA3UZpS\/+EtFi48B3ioz6OFgxwmu0e5xQKc3r++vXrMGniRDg4OL4U+fjxYwQFBiI2Nk4wI4\/i4iJ4eHhgIpvc19cP2VlZCGK7xMOCYyfLoOzs7Mju4ODAQuAwUlNTSPCjR4+oD8fe9D0k6HTFj4LRoKysFPPZPyU+nn+9WMHcnHvOgMjRxHN2Jw6FV9nXxazFZLkcnZ2dghkMPr6np0e0dE7XV6GvtxeBgUvpkuVf6rTF3d2dMhV9g8c1d8lsflqyXdz4WbywvBqSRdbX36OHOzo60R9nbUlO3szeWq\/opV+sDA+nNbi6ukEtXFwKJIs8e\/YMTZB\/okAwow8el\/zu5tfEcCBZ5O6vdlHWUs0yi8rKSsp3nz59KqyGDckiI8JVtJNyFvD8lxelrS2qdO41Q4VkkQEss+eZxvbtO1iSfQUHDxyAqakJprA0Sq1Wi16GCckiebJQy3JQXWjvq4OHsgRjmJAkkmcb\/Aj\/Ny5fvkQi4+MTBGOYkCSyqakJSqUS73+wXDAacJflIsfEd9delj24u88hQV9nZKKlpYWuFAU7hKysrFnuqd+vbf8XkmOygwnx9vYioebm5vTr6OTE4rRO9DBUAP8AIYccI8xeK0sAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='59' Height= '33' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAADoAAAAhCAYAAACIqrhwAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAZYSURBVFhHzVgJTFRXFB0R2ZFNtqDWLhZZrRVICmXRooDWptpUrba0VZAoFMWlRqqiNhEaLabVBDSsblWgAQSExJViBSpgRJZqBRQUQWRfKqCevnfnYQadBAahmZO8zLvn3fn\/n\/\/fXf6XYIRISjqNgIAAGuHh4WhubhYryokRCQ3dtg2qqqrw8fHBqlWroKmpCVc3N\/T19wsP5YPCQs+fOweJRILAwCDBAGezsogL+i5YMMoHhYWWlZUhJCQEdXX3BQP09vaSUBcXV8EoH0Yco7LIOJNOQvft2y8Y5cNrC21ufoxJRkawtJyBjo5OwSofXkto6Y0beGPqFJiZmaOiolKwyokRC83JzoamhgasbWzR0NAoWOXFiISeSU+jmPxixUrBKD8UFnrv7l16klbWNrh16xaqq6vplw\/ZTKxsIKHPnz\/HTxERcHZ2hpOTE9atC0RNzV1yeBmbN22ipylvuLm5Cy\/F8O03X2PT5i3CGhtInrJu5suVK+lCly1bjuDgYJpbTJ4sV2zZzZvIyclBNovRLNYoyI7Cwr+El2Iw0NeDnf1MYY0NJL+npJCw8PAIQQF\/5OYSt5Y92bFCH2syurq6aP7O22\/hA2cXmsuCr3d3dwtraPCdOQDpf3uExYTeuXMHBw8dQmtrm6CA9rY2Eurts0Awo4cnT55g544dMDI0hK6uLnwWLGTlyRTuHnOEBxATEwNbGxvo6elBS0uLdVwuuJqfT2v+\/n74fOlSPHv2jGyOixfOw9XVFTUsfxRduwYPd3c6to6ODhYt+gRVVVXyk9Hh6CgSevTYMcGMHraHhtKxv9+6FampqXB0cJDeVG\/pTY2LjSV78ZLPkM1CJDoqionVhLGxCa3vCttJ639evUo2h7ubKwwNjdDZ2QlTExO8y5qXzMxMJCTEk6+trd2rQisryjGOLXqwO9z\/9KlgRwctLc1QV1ODl7ePYMAurgPa7Kl5zJlLdnJSEtav30DzAWwM2UAX3NPzL5oePaL5wAtEw8OHZO\/e\/SNaW1oGrXGUlBQjLY2VQ2ETzmZlQm3CBDg4OKKpqUmwUvBYqa+vH9Zob28X\/xqM4qIiupBffj0oGCk8P5oLB0cnYUmRe\/kyIiMj2Vb1h4WFBbS0dVi72UJrjg6zYWxiSvO42Bg6ZmXl3+CJ1fVDF7JNTE3h6+uLvCtXyO+FUL5FuMPCjxehr+\/V98oDBw5g+vTpwxpBQUGDEsMAePzwc8TFxQtGiiWLP8Xs2Y40z2dbciprK7kfF8hLnrWVFROqzXZEK\/kkxMfRenFJCVxZ\/FpZ2RA\/AL79PT09oaY2gfx8WK4hob+dPEnE7j17yFEeenp60NjYOKzBY0Ue7tfV0XlWr\/YXjBT2drZwFq94VpaWLCZ1BpW2LaJ2V1VVk93CtigPAW9vb6iOH4\/9P0cS39DQgGMsr3Sza+Xo6Oh4EdOSkuJicp41633ks8yWy0rLpUuXaNxkNXO04TVvHp04k9VdjqOJCWQPxO0U9hQnTtRjofOY7JTkZAon7lNQUEgcx4rly4nT0NRkN\/cRcUVF0h3Dd+VAWdoVFkacJHDdWulEzpg\/34ucRxP1Dx7gvZkz6fhmZmbQ1zeAqanJi\/KSyDKliso4WreYbAEN1m7y7cvttPQz5MNx8cIFcY3egpFioHPT0dGFubk5zfeyHkFSW3sPpaWluMFeuV4eNTU14u+ji15WSzMyMnDkyBHqlevrH+D27X\/EKsv8lZWIj49HYmIi7tXWEsevUfYtiffcXETi0VdLYHlZGWJZkuLHLy4uIU5uHR0K169fpy9\/YWxbyI5GlvrHGjz+edOxxs+PxbI2s6Xd1VAYkVDehPO7ybsW2VHBnsRYIyU5CQYGBnT+qOjDgh0aCgvlZcPG2pqacN6Gcbuf1a++vj65JWW00cWe6IkTJ5CXlyeY4UFhoXzrjFdRwYaQjWT\/H+JGAwoL5d+J+LZxYD3qm9OmsaypzzLffJSXVwgP5YTCQk+fOkVCZ8ywwvHjxxEdHQ3jSZNYiTCjDKqsGNHWvcL6xzaZfrawoIDEj\/VXgteBwkLlgTfxXKi8l2dlgcJC+buql5fXoPrFux0u1M9vcA+rTFBYaET4XhIV+sN2snnW9fX9ijjZXlTZMKKtG7BmDdTV1WFvbw87Ozv65JGali5WlRHAf99x3pj74dK\/AAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='63' Height= '36' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAD8AAAAkCAYAAAA+TuKHAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAaUSURBVGhD7Vh5TFRHGF+EIGC5NKywuJwiUCEtYlEqKmhBoVgRmoIcRZPSCn8oWPEiEYqLtkgbqxVsKosHJgoFhdpEWzmi1KYqYGNFoIKJLHKEo4Ioy\/V15nuzdFdbiw9W2cRfMtn5fm\/em\/ebne+YJ4AJQmbmIdiSuJVZmoEJEV9WWgqGhobg6OTMGM3AuMSPDA\/DNwcPgkAgwDZ3rgu7ohkYh\/gR8F66FEWvCQ4GodAM7O0d2DXNAG\/xcnk\/hIWGQUFBIdqWliKwsrLBvqaAt\/iRkRHWAxgeGoKZM4VgbW3LGM3AhAS8ocHBV+JfidcgvBKvwCAR8ejRI2aNHVQ8TXXjjfY0iNL5+\/v7GaNeoPgHDx7A+vXrwNTUFHR1dcHT0xOKi3\/AAWMBFT9tmgHMmCFkDD90dnSQlGkJQUFrGKNeCKhwH2+uWFkbHg7bt28HY2NjtMvKytmwZ4P+Y+Xl5XDp0mXG8EN7WxvOO3\/+W4xRLwSnT53CCeMTNjMKoLb2NnLL3\/FljHohl8txAQcHBnDeRYu82JV\/MERqCW4cI3iA3j9MSnIFBH91d5N\/7BLZ+j2MAujt7cWXWOj5NmPUg+rqavDz8wUDAwMSM2bCrl3JoK+nB15ei9kIOqaKVJKh6JL6+vogtrKCDRti0VXpgkVGREDY2rUqi0LdJyAgAA4f\/hbtjIx9YGdnh\/cLhULYtCke71cJeO3t7bh9\/Xx9wczMDC789DO7MvGouXULZkyfjoscFxcHUZGR2NfS0gIfn+U4pr6uDnS0tZGPJWN27NgBTk6OaIeHR+KYSOKq1K6qqkab4uCBA8hVEi4rMxP7dEGTkpIgwN8f7VWrVquKXxX4Ll6g7b3VQbhN1IUPmdgipcCafeQ75Ly9l6H947lzMGfOHMjLy0dbAXOSVs3MuOD6+41qvGfnziS0KdzefAPMLSyw7+7mBq+R47byztickACJiVtVxVdUVEBlZSVIJBJ8oNfiJWpZAJrKRObmJLKLGcNhYEBOssY0km2edrfOzk6oqamBwoICMDExgVliMW57CmsrMdjY2mG\/6d49fPeNG+PRTojfhLarqysRnEiCeBnyFCrilbF+XTTedPFiCWMASkpKIDY2dsxNeSJldHd3gRZ59oKFT4t83dkR3N3nMwvg6\/378d+n76Lc7B0cSBDkgleaZDdyMlkz5EizsV9dfQOv9RDfjon5CLSZ+9BmReJG7smTIJDJZHDh\/Hno6+vDwQpkHTqEA3NyjjJm4sTTuUyMjMB+9tPnf5GFOXh4LMD+4SzOX93c5kHanj1QWHgG7vx5B8SzZoGFyHJUfO1tLjul7dkLK1f4gS3bBcpob2+D7\/PzMb7Q4KmjowOCxC2f4o1HsqVsGIdlPt7I\/3b1KmMmFu+HBOPzKyp+YQz9HFaCnCLgUd+ldmtrO9oUba0tGLWtbWxV\/Nh93jysT7SnTIFdySnIDZDUSRfjydSZlcn9sYL6+nqwIKutO3UqSQkZUFxUBCHB3ItFR6+DcaTVZ6Ly+jWcw9DQCI4eOwbS7GwwIKIot4iluuioKLRDw8JIxVkM6elfgAkrwExJpuh9+BDHUSh2iba2DjQ0NCJHY0JY6AfIB4eEQBHRJpVKQUgyGQ2Y6PN\/3LwJLi4uOIg2Xd2psHXbNnyAOlFUdBYcHGaPzhtBMoD30iWwmmQaCllTE6k+uR2oaDEffwJxxKXEJOAp\/JqiubkZt7KHx0LGcKB1TFRkhMoznJ2d4dq166oBr6GhASNqV1cXY9QPujXpnI2N3L9FK7AnM4zivVpaWhjDZQy5fIBZAHfvNqKwjC+\/Yowq7t+\/j8+ora1jzDOi\/f+Bpp709HRITU2FlJSU0SaRpGH19KJAd0cdKYbWBAVhgdRKzgdjBW\/xRWfPjG4jehJUNGNjE9yCLwq5J06MvgeN9s8D3uI\/S07GCUtLy+Dx48fY6Fmc\/iqKjxcBugNzc3Ph8uXnP1HyFu+\/cgXo6ekzSzPBSzw9XlqKLMDR0Qky9u2DwMBAUkXF\/GdRM1nBSzyNvgo\/MzWdrpImFQWGJoCX+EYiPiDAn5yrN4yWxTJZE7iyRbhy5VfkJjt4+\/y\/Iff4cRS\/9\/MvGDO5wVt8T0+PyichCnpAouJTd0sYM7nBSzytw+mXnmxpDmM47E1LQ\/FSpZPgZAYv8VVVlSjSiBQ0F8kxt6OjA\/Lz8sihYgpYW9tAH49v\/y8DvLd93ulTIBKJcBEUn7rp0fF5ysuXC4C\/ARHC\/SJOIjYuAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu22":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for question 22:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">If A, B and C are three consecutive odd natural numbers such that seven times A is two less than five times C, what is the sum of A and B? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"20","CORRECT_ANSWER":"20","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu23":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 23 to 25:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">A four-digit number N has 15 factors. How many factors can N<sup>2<\/sup> have? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>29\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>30\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>45\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Either 29 or 45\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu24":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 23 to 25:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:;size:9999999\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Harish and Kavya start from the same point and begin to run in opposite directions on a circular path, of radius 28 m, at speeds of 4 m\/s and 7 m\/s respectively. It is known that at every instance that they meet, they interchange their speeds. What is the time taken by them to meet for the third time at the starting point? (Take <img height=\"39\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAADsAAAAnCAYAAACxMTBTAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAQCSURBVGhD7ZlLKG1hFMePZ2QgBkIhr0gpSmJCyoBMkKRImWBGUZjIK8yQEFESeYUw8FZKEUpJREJ5JpK8n\/\/bWufb+zr37nPvriv3bPf+anXOWq0z+O\/9PdZaRwcT5\/HxEdPT08jOzkZBQQFycnKQlZWFrq4ukaHn5eUFi4uLyM3NRV5eHvLz8zmvtrZWZAAmL3Zqago6nQ7FxcU4Pz\/H3t4eYmJiYGdnh5WVFZEFHB4ewtzcHGlpaTg+PsbJyQkyMzNhaWkpPxiTFzs0NITY2Fjh6VlbW+MHkJ6eLiL6WEREBK6vr0UEuLm5YbHBwcHsm7xYJba3t1lsUlKSiChzf38Pa2tr+Pn5sa9JsX19fSx2YGBARJSRVkBpaSn7mhNLB5aLiwsiIyNFxDi0rN3c3HB7e8u+5sQmJyfD09MTFxcXIqJMWVkZbGxssLGxISIaE0tXipWVFXZ3d0VEmba2Nl6+s7OzIqJHM2Lb29tZwPLysogoMz8\/z3m9vb0i8h1NiF1dXWUBg4ODIqJnf38fb29vwgPOzs5ga2vLS\/g9BwcHXHSYvNjX11cEBAQgIyODfTpsyIaHh+Hv728gNiEhAeHh4Szs7u6O89bX1+Hh4YGnpyfTF1tXV8dvld4Y7VfJKEYPQWJycpJjFhYWfLe+z6NPwuTFdnd3o7q6GuXl5SgpKZGtoqICY2NjIgtcP1dVVXH8fR79rrOzk3M0c0B9BP\/FflX+TbF0hD8\/P\/MRLRn5Uow+tQ6Lra+vh6urK99Hzs7OcHR0ZCPf3d2dv1ObRP2hEhTf3NxUZXTB\/y10PT09iIuL427e3t4eqampXGqRkU8dBn2nS9zY26VpgnSv\/c7i4+PFrz4fHY0vJHx8fNDc3Cw8wNfXFyEhIcIzDlUqW1tbqozGJ2qgyml0dFR+8B9hBgeUt7c3ampqhKf3pZHGZ\/Pw8IDAwEB5S32EyWLpSdL+fD+NUyv29PQU\/f39qoy6ErX8eGD+qcliLy8vYWZmhsbGRhFRL5b6RgcHB1WWkpIifvX5yGJpL1HR3NTUJCLgkYaaPUurgsYlauxvXmGyWOoVSSxdQxJhYWE8imxoaODDQuvIYmkv0cR9aWlJRICFhQVERUXx0qNJnalAQ3Bq6ZRsYmICOzs7ItMQWayWoJqAVqExGx8fF5mGaFJsUVER1wQdHR3c75LRPZqYmMjXlTE0KbaystKgcZegMU1LS4vwfkaTYpVobW3l8pbmT8b4MmK9vLxQWFgoPGW+hNiZmRkuiI6OjkREmS8hNigoSFVlpnmxc3NzfN3QIP13aF5sdHQ0QkNDhfdrNC2W+mN6qyMjIyLyazQtlooIJycnbkTUoFmxV1dX\/JcIVU7qAL4B4Pqcf5FifwMAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"59\" \/> ) <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>32 seconds\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>48 seconds\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>96 seconds\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>None of the above\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu25":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 23 to 25:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">The multiplication of two numbers is shown below: <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhQABOAPcAAP\/\/\/7ZmAABmtv\/bkDoAAAAAAGa2\/\/\/\/tmYAZrb\/\/zo6ZmY6OpDb\/zoAZmYAAAAAZtuQOjqQ2\/+2ZgA6kNv\/\/wBmZmYAOjo6kLb\/tv\/\/25A6AAAAOrbbkJA6ZmaQkJBmkEBAQDoAOpBmAJCQOgAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAQABOAAAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihQYQMDAAQQKqCxgoOABBAlGIhygYAEDgQMaxARwwEHLgQEe7JRZEEIEozh1DpQwgYJACRVgEnVpgcGAC05zDn0Z8yUGqVOXmsygoaXWgVwBGE0bluTKAibPCuR6lQLbsHIPVJULgCkFCG833AyLFGiEvD4J3iWqd3BSDilX\/kQLtq3ly5gza97MubPnz6BDf0QZ2LFovp4zdOgKFrVnCQU8KE06FLQEoQRJr2zaGbbsoa45Z\/jglG1w0bSRH9QtWbnz59CjSzcI4q3169iza88OYrr37+DDi6EfT768+fPlSxKEXQA3Twftd\/YsIHgqTZs4Q9z0CyBABLUm9fcffzIZVZgEAXKVllbHhdRYXQX5dVZjTIlAn2khIQgAWZO9ZxZWPFUFW0sEihTAWwECgNJPE4qIW2Mj5VVVX\/XNJRWDSsEoUmEkHaZfQf4BuKEG\/0HAm4MzntTACG+9CJ9787mH3pRUVmnllRlVt92WXHbZHZZghinmmM4FBAA7\" style=\"width: 64px; height: 78px;\" \/><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">If A, D, and E are all distinct digits, find the value of A + E. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>9\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>11\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>10\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu26":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 26 and 27:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">The top speed of a rail engine is 80 km\/hr. When pulling a train of wagons, its top speed is reduced by a quantity proportional to the square-root of the number of wagons. When the number of wagons attached to the engine is 25, its top speed is 55 km\/hr. If the top speed must be more than 20 km\/hr, what is the maximum number of wagons that can be attached to the engine? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"143","CORRECT_ANSWER":"143","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu27":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 26 and 27:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Amit took a car loan of Rs.3,31,000 at an interest rate of 10% per annum compounded annually. The loan has to be repaid in three equal annual instalments. Find the amount (in Rs.) which Amit has to pay at the end of each year. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"133100","CORRECT_ANSWER":"133100","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu28":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 28 and 29:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">In an exam, Arun&rsquo;s mark was 25% more than the pass mark, which, in turn, was 25% less than Varun&rsquo;s mark. If the difference between the marks of Arun and Varun is 20, then find the pass mark. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>320\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>240\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>300\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>None of these\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu29":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for questions 28 and 29:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">The marks of seven students form a geometric progression. If the marks that the students got were all distinct integers and the maximum marks that any student could have got is 100, which of the following could be the marks of one of the students? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>64\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>81\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>75\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>36\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu30":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for question 30:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">How many four-digit numbers exist for which the product of the digits is equal to 18? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"36","CORRECT_ANSWER":"36","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu31":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for question 31:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Find the largest number which divides 676, 1596 and 3206 leaving the same remainder in each case. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>240\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>230\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>460\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>None of the above\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu32":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for question 32:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">If &lsquo;&ge;&rsquo; represents multiplication, &lsquo;&le;&rsquo; represents addition, &lsquo;&lt;&rsquo; represents subtraction, and &lsquo;&gt;&rsquo; represents division, find the value of 54 &ge; 3 &le; 132 &gt; 3 &lt; 47. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"159","CORRECT_ANSWER":"159","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu33":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for question 33:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Consider the following system of equations in the unknowns <i>p<\/i>, <i>q<\/i><i> <\/i>and <i>r<\/i>: <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><i>p<\/i> + 5<i>q<\/i>&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span>&minus;<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&nbsp;4<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">r<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> = <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x<\/i><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">3<i>p<\/i>&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span>&minus;<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">&nbsp;<i>q<\/i> + 8<i>r<\/i> = <i>y<\/i> <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">2<i>p<\/i>&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span>&minus;<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">&nbsp;10<i>q<\/i> + 17r = <i>z<\/i> <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Which one of the following conditions must the arbitrary constants <i>x<\/i>, <i>y<\/i> and <i>z<\/i> satisfy so that the above system of simultaneous equations has at least one solution? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">7<i>x<\/i>&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span>&minus;<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">&nbsp;5<i>y<\/i> + 6<i>z<\/i> = 0 <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT2":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">7<i>x<\/i> + 5<i>y<\/i>&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span>&minus;<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">&nbsp;9<i>z<\/i> = 0 <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT3":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">7<i>x<\/i>&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span>&minus;<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">&nbsp;5<i>y<\/i> + 4<i>z<\/i> = 0 <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT4":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">7<i>x<\/i>&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span>&minus;<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">&nbsp;5<i>y<\/i> + 3<i>z<\/i> = 0 <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu34":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<strong>DIRECTIONS&nbsp;<\/strong><em>for question 34:&nbsp;<\/em><span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">The number of integral values of <i>x<\/i> that satisfy | |<i>x<\/i> - 6| - |<i>x<\/i> + 3| | &le; 5 is&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"6","CORRECT_ANSWER":"6","UNIT":".","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"}}